trendsmap.com 2019-04-28

# Trendsmap - Privacy

This is the privacy notice of **Trendsmap Pty Ltd.** In this document, "we" or "us" refers to Trendsmap Pty Ltd.

We are ACN158 718 364, ABN 96 963 894 581 registered in Australia.

This is a notice to tell you our policy about all information that we record about you. It covers both information that could identify you and information that could not.

We are extremely concerned to protect your privacy and confidentiality. We understand that all users of our web site are quite rightly concerned to know that their data will not be used for any purpose unintended by them, and will not accidentally fall into the hands of a third party. Our policy is both specific and strict. It complies with Australian law. If you think our policy falls short of your expectations or that we are failing to abide by our policy, do please tell us.

We regret that if there are one or more points below with which you are not happy, your only recourse is to leave our web site immediately.

Trendsmap only analyses Twitter data that is made publicly available

Except as set out below, we do not share, or sell, or disclose to a third party, any personally identifiable information collected at this site.

Here is a list of the information we collect from you, either through our web site or because you give it to us in some other way, and why it is necessary to collect it:

## 1\. Basic identification and contact information.

When you register and log in to our Services using your social network account, we receive basic personal details from your social network profile. The scope of details we receive depends on your social network account privacy settings; however, they might include public profile information (such as name, profile picture, gender, age range, or country), e-mail address, hometown and current city. If you wish to alter the amount of personal information that we receive upon your registration, you should review the privacy policy on your social network’s website and change your privacy settings.

This information is used:

1.1. to provide you with the services which you request;

1.2. for verifying your identity for security purposes;

1.3. for marketing our services and products;

1.4. information which does not identify any individual may be used in a general way by us or third parties, to provide class information, for example relating to demographics or usage of a particular page or service.

For purposes of analysis and improvement of our Services, our servers may automatically record information when you visit our website or use some of our Services, including:

1.5. URL;

1.6. IP address;

1.7. Browser type and language; and

1.8. Date and time of your request.

## 2\. Email addresses

Your domain name and e-mail address are recognised by our servers and the pages that you visit are recorded. We shall not under any circumstances divulge your e-mail address to any person who is not an employee or contractor of ours and who does not need to know, either generally or specifically. This information is used:

2.1. to correspond with you or deal with you as you expect.

2.2. in a collective way not referable to any particular individual, for the purpose of quality control and improvement of our site;

2.3. to send you news about the services to which you have signed up;

2.4. to tell you about other of our services or services of sister web sites;

2.5. in order to inform you of the status of your subscription.

You may unsubscribe from informational newsletters from your account page

## 3\. Website usage information

We may use software embedded in our website (such as JavaScript) to collect information about which pages you view and how you reach them, what you do when you visit a page, the length of time you remain on the page, and how we perform in providing content to you. We do not presently associate such information with an identifiable person.

## 4\. Financial information relating only to your credit cards

This information is never taken by us either through our website or otherwise. At the point of payment, you are transferred to a secure page on the website of PIN. That page is not controlled by us. Our staff and contractors never have access to it.

## 5\. Business and personal information

This includes all information given to us in the course of your business and ours, such as information you give us in your capacity as our client. We undertake to preserve the confidentiality of the information and of the terms of our relationship. It is not used for any other purpose. We expect you to reciprocate this policy.

We keep information which forms part of our business record for minimum of six years. That is because we may need it in some way to support a claim or defence in court. That is also the period within which our tax collecting authorities may demand to know it.

## 6\. Third party advertising

Third parties may advertise on our web site. In doing so, those parties, their agents or other companies working for them may use technology that automatically collects your IP address when they send an advertisement that appears on our site to your browser. They may also use other technology such as cookies or Javascript to personalise the content of, and to measure the performance of their adverts. We do not have control over these technologies or the data that these parties obtain. Accordingly, this privacy notice does not cover the information practices of these third parties. Note that we don't put advertising on our paid subscription services.

## 7\. Cookies

Trendsmap requires the use of cookies for full operation of the site. Turning off cookies would result in no access to the site, and you being unable to log in. We recommend that you allow the use of cookies in order to take advantage of the features of our website that rely on their use. Here are the ways we use cookies:

7.1. to allow essential parts of our web site to operate for you.

7.2. to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to improve your experience of our site and enable us to increase sales. This cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from, and the pages they visited.

Note that we do not currently support Do Not Track browser preference given the currently limited industry-standard support

## 8\. Credit reference

To assist in combating fraud, we share information with credit reference agencies so far as it relates to clients or customers who instruct their credit card issuer to cancel payment to us without having first provided an acceptable reason to us and given us the opportunity to refund their money.

## 9\. Sending a message to our support system

When you send a message, we collect the data you have given to us in that message in order to obtain confirmation that you are entitled to receive the information and to provide to you the information you need. We record your request and our reply in order to increase the efficiency of our business / organisation. We do not keep any personally identifiable information associated with your message, such as your name or email address. When you contact us you must use a valid email address so that we can reply to you.

## 10\. Complaining

When we receive a complaint, we record all the information you have given to us. We use that information to resolve your complaint. If your complaint reasonably requires us to contact some other person, we may decide to give to that other person some of the information contained in your complaint. We do this as infrequently as possible, but it is a matter for our sole discretion as to whether we do give information, and, if we do, what that information is.

We may also compile statistics showing information obtained from this source to assess the level of service we provide, but not in a way that could identify you or any other person.

## 11\. Third party content

Trendsmap website is built using data provided by the Third Party Twitter. We have no control of content posted on Twitter which may then appear on Trendsmap. If you provide information to Twitter with a view to it being read, copied, downloaded or used by other people, we accept no responsibility for that information as it may be used by Trendsmap. It is up to you to satisfy yourself about the privacy level of every person who might see your information. If it is available to the entire World, you have no control whatever as to how it is used.

We do not moderate or control what is posted. If you complain about any of the content on our web site, we shall investigate your complaint. If we feel it may be justified, we shall remove it if the information is hosted by us. We can not remove images/posts hosted by a third party. If we think your complaint is vexatious or without any basis, we shall not correspond with you about it.

## 12\. Information we obtain from third parties

Although we do not disclose your personal information to any third party (except as set out in this notice), we do receive data which is indirectly made up from your personal information, from Twitter. 

We only display information obtained from Twitter with their terms and conditions, and will remove deleted, or now private information that was once public on Twitter

Note that any social media data published on Twitter may be re-published as per Twitter's terms and conditions by other sites including Trendsmap

## 13\. Use of site by children 

If you are under 18, you may use our site only with consent from a parent or guardian. The site may contain information unsuitable for children viewers and parents should be responsible for children that may view this site. We do not market to children.

Sharing your personal data for legal and business purposes. 

## 14\. Sharing your personal data for legal reasons

We may use and/or disclose to third parties (including government bodies and law enforcement authorities) information about you when:

14.1 Complying with legal process;

14.2 Enforcing or defending the legal rights of Trendsmap;

14.3 Preventing fraud or imminent harm; and

14.4 Ensuring the security of our network and services.

## 15\. Update personal Information

At any time you may review or update the personally identifiable information that we hold about you, by contacting us via our contact page or via email. To better safeguard your information, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to your information.

## 16\. Sale of your personal information

Except as specified above, we do not rent, sell or otherwise disclose any of your information to any person outside our business.

## 17\. Data may be “processed” outside Australia

Our web sites are hosted in datacenters both inside and outside Australia. Our technical centre is based in Melbourne, Australia. Accordingly data obtained within Australia may be “processed” outside Australia and data obtained in any other country may be processed within or outside that country.

## 18\. Compliance with the law

This privacy policy has been compiled so as to comply with the law of every jurisdiction in which we aim to do business. If you think it fails to satisfy the laws of your country, please contact our privacy support staff via our email or contact page. Ultimately it is your choice as to whether you wish to use our website.

## 19\. Change in Privacy Policy

As we plan to ensure our privacy policy remains current, this policy is subject to change. Please return periodically to review our privacy policy.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at anytime. Your continued use of our services which are subject to our Privacy Policy will signify your acceptance of any or all changes

If you have any question regarding the privacy policy, please contact us through the contact page.
